Guide to the Armenian Nationality Room Committee Collection, 1975-2011 UA.40.20.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Multimedia, 1982-2001; V.
  - Photographs, 1985-1995; 1.
    This subseries is composed of photographs, photographic prints, and 35mm slides that depict events regarding the planning, fundraising, building, and use of the Armenian Nationality Room.
    - Photographs, 1985 (Map-case 26, Folder 12)
      This folder contains three packets of photographs and sixteen individually sleeved photographs about the committee trip to Armenia.
    - Photographs, circa 1985 (Map-case 26, Folder 13)
      This folder contains negatives about the committee trip Armenia and classroom construction.
    - Photographs, 1985 (Map-case 26, Folder 14)
      This folder contains thirteen plastic photograph sleeves with photographs about the committee trip to Armenia.
    - Photographs, circa 1987 (Map-case 26, Folder 15)
      This folder contains thirty individually sleeved black and white photographs about the classroom during and after construction.
    - Photographs, 1987 (Map-case 26, Folder 16)
      This folder contains classroom construction photographs.
    - Photographs, 1985, 1987-1988, 1990 (Map-case 26, Folder 17)
      This folder contains 90 slides (five slide preserver sheets) of the construction of the classroom, post-construction, the other Nationality Rooms, an Armenian religious ceremony in Heinz Chapel, the incorporation of the katchkar in the classroom, the Armenia trip, and the Armenian Nationality Room Committee with E. Maxine Bruhns.
    - Photographs, 1985-1988 (Map-case 26, Folder 18)
      This folder contains two envelopes of photographs of Armenian Nationality Room photographs of the Armenian Nationality Room and sketch designs.
    - Photographs, circa 1988 (Map-case 26, Folder 19)
      This folder contains two envelopes of photographs of the Armenian Nationality Room Committee and room dedication.
    - Photographs, post 1988 (Map-case 26, Folder 20)
      This folder contains black and white photographs of the Armenian Nationality Room post-construction.
    - Photographs, 1990 (Map-case 26, Folder 21)
      This folder contains nine contact sheets and plastic sleeves of the classroom post-construction and of the delivery of the katchkar.
    - Photographs, circa 1995 (Map-case 26, Folder 22)
      This folder contains open house photographs of the classroom, photographic prints of Vazgen I, Catholics of All Armenians, and black and white pictures of the katchkar.
    - Photographs, Undated (Map-case 26, Folder 23)
      This folder contains several undated photographic negatives.
    - Binder, circa 1987 (Box 4, Slide 1)
      This binder is separated from the other photograph folders. It contains 311 slides (twenty-two preserver pages) about the furniture, decorations, construction, dedication, and prototypes of the Armenian Nationality Room. There are also slides of Armenian landscapes used for inspirations: Haghbat, Sanahin, Ararat, and Garni. There are also slides of Alice and Charles Klanian, a party for the Armenian Nationality Room stakeholders, and the installation of the donated katchkar.
  - Video, 1982-2001; 2.
    This subseries contains a 3/4" umatic video tape, and two VHS.
    - "WTAE's AM Pittsburgh", April 23, 1982; 3/4" Umatic Video Tape (Box 4, Item 1)
    - "Armenian Nationality Committee of America Armenian Genocide Observation at the U.S. Capitol", 2001; Video Tape (Box 4, Item 2)
    - "Dedication of the Armenian Room", 1988; Video Tape (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Audio, 1988-1992; 3.
    This subseries contains eight audio cassettes, two scripts, and two 1/4" audio tape.
    - "Classroom Presentation", Undated; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 4)
    - "Armenian Room Master/With Music", 1992; 1/4" Audio Tape (Box 4, Item 5-6)
    - "Armenian Room Master", 1991; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 7-8)
    - "Armenian Room Copy", 1991; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 9)
    - "Armenian Room Dedication", 1988; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 10)
    - "Armenian Music: Richard Yardumian", circa 1988-1991; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 11)
    - "Armenian Music", circa 1988-1991; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 12)
    - "Armenian Room Pan", circa 1988-1991; Audio Cassette (Box 4, Item 13)
    - Armenian Room Tape Tour Script, 1991 (Box 4, Item 14-15)
- 2001 Deposit, 1975-1988; VI.
  This series contains the 2001 deposit of records from the Armenian Nationality Room.
  - History, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - History (AACP), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - National Geographic, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Symposium, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Concept & Design, undated (Box 5, Folder 6-13)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Mangooian, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Shakarian, undated (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
  - Construction, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Construction, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Construction, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Construction Meetings, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dedication, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Background Information, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)